A Guide to the Sigrid L. Rupp Architectural Collection, 1950-2004
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Sigrid L. Rupp Architectural Collection, 1950-2004
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1997-006
219.0 cu. ft.
Sigrid L. Rupp (1943-2004) was principal architect of her own firm, SLR/Architects in Palo Alto, California from 1976 to 1998. Born in Germany in 1943, she relocated to California with her family in 1953. She earned a B. Arch. from the University of California, Berkeley in 1966. SLR/Architects specialized in technical facilities and industrial work providing architectural services for many of the pre-eminent Silicon Valley firms in the 1980s and 1990s. The collection consists of architectural drawings, photographs, administrative and job files, contracts, and other material relating to over 700 of Rupp's projects, as well as material relating to Rupp's personal travel and artistic endeavors. The materials in the collection range in date from 1950-2004 with the bulk of the material dating 1976-2004.
Rupp, Sigrid Lorenzen
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Sigrid L. Rupp Architectural Collection was donated to Special Collections in 1997 with additions arriving in 2004 and 2006.
Biographical Note
Sigrid Lorenzen Rupp was born January 3, 1943, in Bremerhaven, Germany. Her family relocated to California when Rupp was ten years old (1953). Rupp had been fascinated with the built environment since her early childhood growing up in post-war reconstruction Germany. However, when she entered University of California-Berkeley, in 1960, she had won many small scholarships to study physics. Her physics career lasted two semesters after which she was able to convince everyone that she should study her first love, architecture (Boulgarides).
While at Berkeley Rupp was mentored by three renowned architects and professors, Joseph Esherick, AIA, Harold Stump, and Donald Reay. Upon graduation in 1966 with a Bachelor of Architecture, Rupp worked for Van Bourg/Nakamura Associates of San Francisco, D'Amico Associates of Mill Valley, Hawley & Peterson of Mountain Valley and Spencer Associates of Palo Alto. During this time she received her architecture license in the State of California (1971).
In 1976, Rupp stating that architecture was in the "doldrums" and recognizing that there was no future for her in the 'major firm' where she was currently employed decided to open her own firm exclaiming, "I could do nothing on my own as well as for someone else"(Boulgarides). She served as president and principle architect for SLR/Architects from 1976 until 1998 when she closed the office.
SLR/Architects specialized in technical facilities, industrial work, and residential structures. The company provided architectural services for many of the pre-eminent Silicon Valley firms: Apple Computer, Sun Microsystems, Tandem, Amdahl, Claris, Raychem, and IBM. Other prominent clients included: AT&T, Pac Bell, United Airlines, Pan Am, Stanford University and Hospital and San Jose State University. Some of her significant projects were the Press Building and Storey House at Stanford University, an RF Testing Facility for Apple Computer (winner of an AIA Honor Award), and a six-year factory retrofit and rehab for the Raychem Corporation. At its height SLR/Architects employed eight professional and paraprofessional staff (1987) and established an international branch SLR/International in Tel Aviv, Israel (1983).
Rupp was active in many professional and local civic organizations. She was a former board member and chairperson of the City of Palo Alto Architectural Review Board, former director of the Santa Clara Valley Chapter of the American Institute of Architects and former president of California Women in Environmental Design (CWED). She also served on the boards of the New Performance Gallery in San Francisco, Theater Artaud of San Francisco, Family Planning Alternatives of Sunnyvale, Diablo Ballet of Walnut Creek and the Lawrence Pech Dance Company of San Francisco. She was an active member of the Organization of Women Architects (OWA), the American Institute of Architects (AIA), the Construction Specifications Institute (CSI) and the Union Internationale des Femmes Architectes (UIFA).
An ardent champion for women’s rights, Rupp stated that she became involved in women’s issues “…simply because I did not want there to be any [women's issues]. It seemed that the time for gender differences should be long over." She was a mentor to many women and minorities in the course of her practice encouraging and facilitating their entry into architecture.
In retirement, Rupp turned her attention to painting and traveling. Her watercolors primarily focused on California bay area landscapes and were featured in several local juried shows. She also traveled extensively documenting her experiences in beautifully illustrated and annotated travel diaries (present in the collection).
Sigrid Lorenzen Rupp passed away May 27, 2004. Her legacy in her own words, "I'd like to be remembered for dissenting when everyone else thought it easier to go with the grain even when the grain was wrong. I'd like to be remembered for being a competent architect who did competent work, a competent painter who did competent painting and someone who told good stories” (OWA).
~~~~~~~~~~~
References:
"Dr. James D. Boulgarides, Study Looking at Women in Architecture," Sigrid Lorenzen Rupp Architectural Collection (Ms1997-006) Special Collections, University Libraries, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University.
(Organization of Women Architects and Design Professionals 2004) http://owa-usa.org/newsletter/jul04.htm
Scope and Content
Rupp's collection encompasses over twenty years of her firm, SLR/Architects, and includes administration and project files, sketches, drawings, blueprints, slides and photographs representing approximately 700 designs. The collection also contains Rupp's personal papers -- biographical information, student work, travel diaries and photographs, and artwork. The materials range in date from 1950-2004 (bulk 1976-2004) and are divided into five series: Personal Papers, Professional Papers, Office Records, Project Records, and Art and Artifacts. See the contents list below for more detail about the individual series.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
See also Ms1990-059 California Women in Environmental Design Records, 1990-1994.
Index Terms
Genre and Form Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Diaries.; Photographs.; watercolors (paintings)
Occupations:
Architects.
Subjects:
Women travelers--Asia; Women travelers--Europe; Women travelers--South America; Women travelers--United States; Women-owned architectural firms.
Local Subjects:
International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA)
Contents List
- SERIES I. Personal Papers, 1954-2004.
  Scope and Content
  The Personal Papers series contains Rupp's biographical information, student work, diaries/journals, photographs, and personal correspondence. The series also contains Rupp's extensive documentation of her travels in Europe, Asia, North and South America, formats include, travel diaries, watercolor (paintings), photographs (prints, negatives and slides), photo albums, and miscellaneous ephemera.
  - SUBSERIES I: General, 1954-2004.
    - 60th Birthday Celebration: January 10, 2003.
      - Birthday Cards. (Box 63)
      - Birthday Haiku. (Box 63)
      - Guest List. (Box 63)
      - Invitation. (Box 63)
      - Printed Photographs. (Box 63)
    - Accordion book featuring watercolor of residence (series of images include site plans, elevations, floor plans, etc), 1995. (Box 63)
    - Artist statement for SLR's waterscapes, draft, undated. (Box 63)
    - Autograph Book, [friends and schoolmates in Germany], 1954, 1956. (Box 63)
    - Biographical Information, 1966; 1997; 2004. (Box 63)
    - Dance Review for Men Dancing XIV, Presented by the Gary Palmer Dance Co. of San Jose [CA], September 1995. (Box 63)
    - Day Calendars, 1979; 1982-1998. (Box 63)
    - Guest Book, 1983-1984. (Box 63)
    - Invitation [Party], undated. (Box 152)
    - Japanese characters, undated. (Box 63)
    - Legal Documents, 1967. (Box 63)
    - Milligton, Peter Sherfy [self published book of poetry by Millington inscribed to Rupp], January 1990. (Box 63)
    - Notebook [includes three pages of miscellaneous re: Tibet, a light fixture, women traveling, and a quote by John Muir]. (Box 63)
    - Personal ad, draft. (Box 63)
    - Postcards. (Box 63)
    - Scrapbook [from Rupp's high school years], 1959-1960. (Box 151)
    - Yearbooks, Fremont High School, Oakland, CA, 1958-1960. (Box 63)
  - SUBSERIES II: Correspondence, 1966-2004.
    - General, 1966; 1968; 1987; 1998-1999; 2004. (Box 64)
    - Steven Rupp, 1966-1967. (Box 64)
    - Ken G., 1967-1976. (Box 64)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Harry Lorenzen [Rupp's father], 1968; 2002. (Box 64)
    - Masakazu and Izumi Kishikawa, 1998; 2000; and undated. (Box 64)
    - Milka Blitznakov, 2002-2004. (Box 64)
  - SUBSERIES III: Diaries/Journals, 1970-2004.
    - 1970. (Box 63)
    - 1982 [includes 2 photographs of Rupp]. (Box 63)
    - [Dream Diary], 1983, 1986. (Box 63)
    - 1987; 1988; 1993 [writing notes; names and addresses; financial notes]. (Box 63)
    - "An Age of Possibilities," includes democratic meeting in Washington, D.C.; trip to Monterey, CA; trip to Seattle, WA; notes about lectures; EPA (East Palo Alto) redevelopment; and an Ikea coming to Palo Alto (2001)]. (Box 64)
    - Diary of an Illness, December 1, 2003 - [March 22, 2004]. (Box 64)
  - SUBERIES VI: Travel, 1966-2003.
    Arrangement
    Many of the trips within the Travel subseries are represented in a variety of formats (e.g. a trip may have prints, negatives, slides, photo albums, or a travel diary within the collection). To facilitate discovery a Travel Index has been created listing the formats available for the most documented trips. NOTE: This is not an exhaustive list of Rupp's travel documentation for that please see the container list below.
    - General, 1968-2003.
      - [18 month tour, Canada, Europe, United Kingdom], 1968. (Box 64)
      - China, 1982. (Box 64)
      - China, black and white proof sheets, 1982. (Box 64)
      - Egypt, March-April 1989. (Box 64)
      - Jordan/Israel, 1995. (Box 64)
      - Italy, France, Spain, 1996. (Box 64)
      - Summer Trip, 1997. (Box 64)
      - Japan, Photographs, 1998. (Box 64)
      - Mexico, November 1998; December 1999. (Box 64)
      - Germany, April 1-April 10, 2000. (Box 64)
      - Mongolia, July/August, 2000. (Box 64, Box 65)
      - China, October 2003. (Box 65)
      - Miscellaneous Panoramic Photographs, undated. (Box 65)
    - Diaries, 1968-2003.
      - [18 Month Tour, Canada, Europe, United Kingdom], 1968. (Box 65)
      - Paris, wine tasting, 1978. (Box 65)
      - Scotland and Upper England, 1981. (Box 65)
      - Pescadores, [CA], 1982, 1985, 1987. (Box 65)
      - Vienna, Budapest, Sofia, Yugoslavia, October 1987. (Box 65)
      - Egypt/Hawaii, Maui, 1989. (Box 65)
      - General Notes, 1991/Travel Notes [1992; Yellowstone, 1992; Drawing 1993; Watercolor 1997; Death Valley, 1999]. (Box 65)
      - Coast along Spain, France, and Italy, June-July, 1994. (Box 65)
      - Israel and Jordon, November 19-30, 1995. (Box 65)
      - Summer Trip, 1997 vol.1 (Palo Alto, CA to St. Ignace, MI via Gulf Coast, Florida, East Coast, Nova Scotia) [has a family tree in the back]. (Box 65)
      - Summer Trip, 1997 vol.2 (St. Ignace to home [Palo Alto, CA]). (Box 65)
      - Peru, January 1998. (Box 65)
      - Trips, 1998 [Carmel, CA; Washington, D.C.; North Carolina; Tennessee; Virginia; and Mexico - Geronimo Educational Studies Tour to San Miguel de Allende/Queretaro; Great Smokies trip has a numbering system that correspondences to photographs]. (Box 65)
      - Mexico Sketchbook, San Miguel de Allende/Queretaro/Guanajuato, November 7-21, 1998. (Box 65)
      - Japan, 1998. (Box 66)
      - Napa Valley; San Juan Capistrano; Santa Catalina, 1999. (Box 66)
      - Mexico, Vera Cruz, November 28-December 8, 1999. (Box 66)
      - Alaska, 1999; 2002. (Box 66)
      - Japan, 2000. (Box 66)
      - Mongolia and Japan, 2000. (Box 66)
      - Sketchbook, [Mongolia; Japan; and Portugal], 2000. (Box 66)
      - In Between Trips, [Atlanta; Germany; Washington, D.C.; California], 2000. (Box 66)
      - Thailand, Cambodia, Vietnam and Singapore, October-December, 2001. (Box 66)
      - Vietnam and Singapore, November-December, 2001. (Box 66)
      - Sketchbook, [Vietnam, Thailand, Cambodia, and Singapore] 2001,. (Box 66)
      - White Sands (Three River Petro glyphs, El Paso, Carlsbad Caverns); Ashland (Columbia River, Sculpture Rocks, Mt. Rainer), 2002. (Box 66)
      - Germany, July 2002. (Box 66)
      - Zion and Bryce National Parks (Utah), March 2003; Washington, D.C. and Baltimore, MD, Emily's List Conference, May 2003; 18th IAWA Meeting, Blacksburg, VA, September, 2003; Canyon Ranch, Arizona, September-October, 2003. (Box 66)
      - China, October 7-28, 2003. (Box 66)
      - Shanghai, undated. (Box 66)
    - Photo Albums, 1975-2002.
      - 1975-1985 [California, Germany, Canada, Great Britian, Utah, China, Israel]. (Box 127)
      - Singapore, 1979; 1985. (Box 133)
      - China, 1982. (Box 136)
      - Israel, 1983, 1985. (Box 135)
      - Chicago and Oak Park, 1986. (Box 135)
      - Bulgaria/Yugoslavia, October 1987. (Box 138)
      - Egypt, 1989. (Box 128)
      - Summer Trip, 1997. (Box 144)
      - 1998 [Peru, Florida, Eastern USA, Japan, Mexico] (includes a written narrative). (Box 130)
      - Peru, [album made for Milka Bliznakov], 1998. (Box 134)
      - 1999 [Death Valley, Alaska, Mexico]. (Box 131)
      - Alaska, 1999, 2002. (Box 131, Box 132, Box 142)
      - 2000-2001 [Atlanta, Belgium, California, China, France, Germany, Japan, Los Angeles, Mongolia, Portugal, Washington, D.C.]. (Box 140)
      - Mongolia, 2000. (Box 141, Box 140)
      - 2002 [Germany, Oregon]. (Box 142)
    - Photographs, 1966-2003.
      - Foreign Travel, 1967-2003.
        - Prints, 1980-2003.
          - Canada, 1980. (Box 95)
          - England/Scotland, 1981. (Box 95)
          - China, October 1982. (Box 95, Box 64)
          - Around the World Trip, 1985 [Hong Kong, Singapore, and Israel]. (Box 95)
          - Bulgaria/Yugoslavia, 1987. (Box 95)
          - Egypt, 1989. (Box 95)
          - Israel and Jordan, 1995. (Box 95)
          - Spain, Italy, and France, 1996. (Box 96)
          - Peru, 1998. (Box 97)
          - Japan, 1998. (Box 64, Box 97)
          - Mexico, 1998-1999. (Box 98, Box 97)
          - Japan, 2000. (Box 98)
          - Mongolia, 2000. (Box 64, Box 98)
          - Thailand, Vietnam, and Cambodia, 2001. (Box 98, Box 99)
          - Germany, 2002. (Box 99)
          - China, 2003. (Box 100, Box 99)
          - Undated.
            - unidentified photographs [travel, Canada?]. (Box 100)
            - Antigua. (Box 100)
            - Antwerp [Belgium]. (Box 100)
            - Ghent [Belgium]. (Box 100)
            - Brugge [Bruges, Belgium]. (Box 100)
            - North sea. (Box 100)
            - Rouen [France]. (Box 100)
            - Normandie [Normandy, France]. (Box 100)
            - Mont St. Michel [France]/Bretagne [Brittany, France]. (Box 100)
            - Chartes, Chambord, Chenonceaux [Chenonceau], Amboise [France]. (Box 100)
            - Paris - old. (Box 100)
            - Paris - new. (Box 100)
            - Medoc Pauillac. (Box 100)
            - Unidentified. (Box 100)
        - Negatives,., 1978-2003
          - Belgium and Cologne, October 1978. (Box 117)
          - Singapore, October 1979. (Box 117)
          - Vancouver, B.C., November 1979/Singapore, 1979. (Box 117)
          - England/Scotland, 1981. (Box 117)
          - China, 1982. (Box 117)
          - Around the World Trip, 1985 (Hong Kong, Singapore, and Israel). (Box 117)
          - Bulgaria/Yugoslavia, October 1987. (Box 117)
          - Egypt, March-April, 1989. (Box 118)
          - Italy, France, Spain, 1994. (Box 118)
          - Jordan/Israel, 1995. (Box 119)
          - Peru, 1998. (Box 119)
          - Japan, 1998. (Box 119, Box 101)
          - Mexico, 1998, 1999. (Box 120)
          - Mongolia, 2000. (Box 120, Box 106)
          - Germany, 2000. (Box 120)
          - Thailand, Cambodia, and Vietnam, 2001. (Box 101, Box 121)
          - Germany, 2002. (Box 121)
          - China, 2003. (Box 121)
        - Slides, 1967-2001.
          - Europe, 1960s--.
            - Rome. (Box 107A)
            - Berlin. (Box 107A, Box 107B)
            - Barcelona. (Box 107B)
            - England/Belgium. (Box 107B)
            - Denmark/Sweden. (Box 107B)
            - Russia. (Box 107C)
            - Greece/Turkey. (Box 107C)
            - Turkey/Bulgarian. (Box 107C, Box 107D)
          - Canada/Iceland. (Box 107D)
          - Mexico. (Box 107D)
          - No Description. (Box 107D, Box 107E)
          - Architecture highlights. (Box 107E, Box 107F)
          - France/Rome, undated. (Box 108A)
          - Canada, 1967. (Box 108A)
          - Germany/Mexico, 1967. (Box 108A)
          - France, 1978. (Box 108B)
          - Germany, 1978. (Box 108B)
          - Singapore, 1979. (Box 108B)
          - Hong Kong, 1979. (Box 108B)
          - Scotland, 1981. (Box 108C)
          - China, 1982. (Box 108C)
          - Singapore, 1985. (Box 108D)
          - Italy, France, and Spain, 1994. (Box 108E, Box 108D, Box 109A, Box 108F, Box 109B)
          - Jordan/Israel, 1995. (Box 109B, Box 109D, Box 109C)
          - Mexico, 1998-1999. (Box 109E)
          - Mongolia, 2000. (Box 109E)
          - Thailand, Vietnam, and Cambodia, 2001. (Box 109E)
      - Domestic Travel, [some groupings include Canada], 1979-2003.
        - Prints, 1989-2002.
          - Boston/Detroit/Indianapolis, 1989. (Box 92)
          - Highway 2 from Washington to Michigan, Summer 1993. (Box 92)
          - Indianapolis and Columbus, Indiana, October 1993. (Box 92)
          - Summer Trip, [circumnavigation of the United States], 1997. (Box 92, Box 64, Box 93)
          - Southeast, US, [University of Virginia, Blue Ridge Parkway, Biltmore House, North Carolina, Washington, D.C.], 1998. (Box 93)
          - Alaska, 1999. (Box 93, Box 64)
          - Alaska,2002. (Box 93, Box 64)
          - Arizona deserts. (Box 94)
          - Baylands: Palo Alto, Mt. View, Redwood City. (Box 94)
          - Big Sur. (Box 94)
          - Blue Ridge Parkway. (Box 94)
          - Bryce Canyon, Utah. (Box 94)
          - California north coast and redwoods. (Box 94)
          - California wine country. (Box 94)
          - Columbia River - sea to Gorges and the Dalles. (Box 94)
          - Death Valley. (Box 94)
          - Joshua National Forest. (Box 94)
          - Los Angeles. (Box 94)
          - Oregon coast. (Box 94)
          - Pescadero Tahana. (Box 94)
          - Seattle/Tacoma. (Box 94)
          - Miscellaneous Panoramic Prints. (Box 64)
          - Kolob Canyon. (Box 94)
          - Zion National Park. (Box 94)
          - Nevada and Vernal Falls. (Box 94)
          - McGurk Meadow [Yosemite]. (Box 94)
          - Half dome and trail [Yosemite]. (Box 94)
          - Yosemite. (Box 94)
          - White Sands, NM. (Box 94)
          - Washington, D.C.. (Box 94)
          - Utah landscapes. (Box 94)
        - Negatives,., 1979-2003
          - 1979-1992.
            - Seattle, Puget Sound, June 1979. (Box 111)
            - Yosemite, (SLR and Roger Buckhout), October 1981. (Box 111)
            - Calgary, 1982. (Box 111)
            - Detroit, 1982. (Box 111)
            - New York with Alisa, May 1984. (Box 111)
            - Squaw Valley, Summer 1985. (Box 111)
            - San Diego/San Juan Capistrano with Peter, November 1985. (Box 111)
            - Miles Canyon with Steve Rupp, December 1985. (Box 111)
            - Vancouver/Chicago, with Alisa, 1986 [?]. (Box 111)
            - Hawaii, 1986-1987. (Box 111)
            - Cape Cod, 1988. (Box 111)
            - Los Angeles/Museum of Modern Art/Miscellaneous Building, January 1989. (Box 111)
            - St. Louis Arch, May 1989. (Box 111)
            - Cape Cod, August 1989. (Box 111)
            - Disneyland, 1989. (Box 111)
            - Boston/Detroit/Indianapolis, 1989. (Box 111)
            - Hawaii, 1989. (Box 111)
            - Boston/San Francisco, 1990. (Box 111)
            - Hawaii, May 1990. (Box 111)
            - Cape Cod, October 1990. (Box 111)
            - Sea Ranch, November 1990. (Box 111)
            - San Francisco, February 1991. (Box 111)
            - San Diego, 1991. (Box 111)
            - Cape Cod, August 1991. (Box 111)
            - Snowbird, August 1991. (Box 111)
            - Livermore Valley/Wineries, 1991. (Box 111)
            - Salt Lake City, 1991. (Box 111)
            - Snowbird, January 1992. (Box 111)
            - Yellowstone, June 1992. (Box 111)
            - Carmel, November 1992. (Box 111)
          - 1993-2001.
            - Highway 2, Washington to Michigan, Summer 1993. (Box 112)
            - Highway 2, Washington to Michigan, Summer 1993. (Box 112)
            - San Diego/Las Vegas/Hoover Dam to Yosemite, with Sara, January 2000. (Box 112)
            - Indianapolis and Columbus, Indiana, October 1993. (Box 112)
            - Golden Gate Park, March 1994. (Box 112)
            - Travels with Masakazu and Izumi Kishikawa, [Golden Gate Bridge, Yosemite], June 1996. (Box 112)
            - Washington, D.C./Al Gore, June 21, 1996. (Box 112)
            - Seattle to Vancouver, March-April, 1997. (Box 112)
            - Victoria, British Columbia, April 1997. (Box 112)
            - Southeast, US, [University of Virginia, Blue Ridge Parkway, Biltmore House, North Carolina, Washington, D.C.], 1998. (Box 112)
            - Florida/Carmel, 1998. (Box 112)
            - Alaska, 1999. (Box 112)
            - Pacific Coast, with Ochirpurevin Sarantsatsral, December 1999. (Box 112)
            - Los Angeles, January 2000. (Box 112)
            - Atlanta High Museum of Art, March 2000. (Box 112)
            - Washington, D.C., May 2000. (Box 112)
            - Yosemite, with Michaela Manges, Winter 2000. (Box 112)
            - Getty Museum, Los Angeles, December 2000. (Box 112)
            - Joshua Tree National Monument, 2000. (Box 112)
            - Atlanta, 2000. (Box 112)
            - Death Valley, 2000. (Box 112)
          - Summer Trip, 1997. (Box 114)
          - Alaska, 2002. (Box 101)
          - 2002-2003, and undated. (Box 113)
        - Slides, 1966-1993.
          - Various cities and landscaped in the United States. (Box 110B, Box 110A)
  - SUBSERIES V: Student Work, 1950-1966.
    - Primary school reports, Germany, 1950-1953. (Box 64)
    - Klasse 3C, [artwork-primary school, Germany], 1951. (Box 64)
    - American Literature, Fremont High School, 1958. (Box 64)
    - World History, Fremont High School, undated. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 1, UC-Berkeley, Job Site: A Study in Form, 1961. (Box 126)
    - Architecture 2, UC-Berkeley, 1962. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 3, UC-Berkeley, 1962. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 5, UC-Berkeley, 1962. (Box 64)
    - City Planning 111, UC-Berkeley, 1962. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 122, UC-Berkeley, 1963. (Box 64)
    - City Planning 121, UC-Berkeley, 1963. (Box 126)
    - History 144B, UC-Berkeley, 1963. (Box 64)
    - Landscape Architecture 100, UC-Berkeley, 1963. (Box 64)
    - Photomontage, Chinatown: A Glorified Slum, May 29, 1963. (Box 126)
    - Architecture 121, UC-Berkeley, 1964. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 151, UC-Berkeley, 1964. (Box 64)
    - Architecture 198/198A, UC-Berkeley, 1964. (Box 64)